swift a multi-paradigm compiled language created by apple famous for building
swift 是一种由苹果公司创建的多范式编译语言，以构建
apps that grow inside of apple's walled garden it was first introduced in 2014
在苹果围墙花园内生长的应用程序而闻名。它于 2014 年
at the worldwide developers conference and was designed as a modern successor
在全球开发者大会上首次推出，被设计
to objective-c the original apple platform language that had been in use
为 Objective-c 的现代继承者，最初的苹果平台语言拥有
since the 1980s swift interops with objective-c but provides a shorter more
自 1980 年代以来一直在使用 swift 与Objective-c 互操作，但它提供了更短且更
readable syntax and features like memory safety and type inference to improve
易读的语法和功能，例如内存安全和类型推断，以提高
developer productivity today it's used to build mobile apps on ios desktop apps
开发人员的工作效率如今它用于在 ios 上构建移动应用程序 在 mac os 上的桌面应用程序
on mac os wearable apps for watch os but is also open source which means it can
上用于 watch os 的可穿戴应用程序 但它也是开源的，这意味着它
be used to build software outside of apple platforms it compiles to native
可以用于在苹果平台之外构建软件，它可以编译为本地
machine code and is built on top of the llvm tool chain like many other modern
机器代码，并且像许多其他现代语言一样构建在 llvm 工具链之上，
languages however it also supports a readable print loop allowing you to
但是它还支持可读的打印循环，让您可以
experiment with code in a playground without needing to recompile making it a
在操场上试验代码，无需重新编译，使其
great language for beginners in addition it provides memory safety by preventing
成为初学者的好语言，此外它还证明了 通过防止
you from writing unsafe code by default and uses automatic reference counting to
您默认编写不安全的代码来保护内存安全并使用自动引用计数来
manage memory automatically to get started install it then create a file
自动管理内存以开始安装它然后创建一个
ending in.swift your code will start executing in the global scope there's no
以.swift 结尾的文件您的代码将开始在全局范围内执行
need for a main function create a variable with the var keyword followed
不需要主函数使用 var 关键字
by its name and value var creates a mutable variable which means its value
后跟其名称和值创建一个变量 var 创建一个可变变量，这意味着它的值
can change in the future let on the other hand creates an immutable variable
将来可以更改 let另一方面创建一个不可变变量
or constant it uses type inference to strongly type the value as a string but
或常量 它使用类型推断将值强类型为字符串 但是
we can explicitly type it by adding a semicolon after the variable name every
我们可以通过在变量名之后添加分号来显式键入它，每个
variable must be initialized with a value unless the type has a question
变量都必须用一个值初始化，除非该类型有一个
mark which makes it an optional type allowing it to also contain a nil value
问号，这使它成为一个可选类型，允许它也包含一个 nil 值
it also supports optional chaining making it really easy to work with nil
它还支持可选链接使其成为 使用 nil
values functions are declared with the fun keyword and will use named
值函数非常容易使用 fun 关键字声明，
parameters by default place an underscore before the name to use
默认情况下将使用命名参数放置一个und  erscore 在名称之前使用
positional arguments instead now use a backslash with parentheses to
位置参数，现在使用带括号的反斜杠将
interpolate these values into a string functions in swift are first class
这些值插入字符串中
objects they can be passed as arguments used as return values and nested to
create closures it also supports object-oriented patterns like classes
像类和继承这样的模式
and inheritance to encapsulate the var and fung keywords that you just learned
来封装你刚刚学到的 var 和 fung 关键字
now pull up the terminal and run the swift compiler to convert your code into
现在拉起终端并运行swift 编译器将你的代码转换
a high performance executable congratulations your code is now ready
为高性能的可执行文件恭喜你的代码现在已经准备
to seek approval on the apple app store this has been the swift programming
好在苹果应用商店寻求批准了 已经
language in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like this make
是 100 秒内的 Swift 编程语言 如果你想看更多这样的短视频，请
sure to hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and i will
确保点击喜欢按钮并订阅感谢观看，我会
see you in the next one
在下一个看到你